Department of Chemistry Records UA151
Tufts Archival Research Center
- Undergraduate Theses, 1910 -- 1967; UA151.001; 10.8 Linear Feet
  - Determination of impurities in nickel plating baths by means of the Beckman Spectrophotometer, 1949; UA151.001.007.00375; Mitchell, Ruth C. (Box 7)
  - The glycine hydrochlorides and triglycine sulfate, 1949; UA151.001.007.00376; Sigler, Marjorie (Box 7)
  - Effect of acid and sodium silicate solutions on properties of florida silica rock, 1950; UA151.001.007.00377; Kolankiewicz, Leon J. (Box 7)
  - Polarographic analysis of nitro and nitrosobenzene, 1950; UA151.001.007.00378; Linde, Harry W. (Box 7)
  - Equilibrium diagram of the benzene-thiophene system, 1950; UA151.001.007.00379; Murray, William K. (Box 7)
  - Decomposition of dibromo cinnamate ion, 1951; UA151.001.007.00380; Finn, Richard F. (Box 7)
  - Electrochemical analysis, 1951; UA151.001.007.00381; Henderson, William Henry Jr. (Box 7)
  - Solid-liquid equilibrium in the benzene-thiophene system, 1951; UA151.001.008.00382; Wright, David Franklin (Box 8)
  - The effect of cyanide on biochemical oxygen demand, 1952; UA151.001.008.00383; Armstrong, Richard S. (Box 8)
  - Heat capacity measurements and solid-liquid equilibrium in the benzene-thiophene system, 1952; UA151.001.008.00384; Bernardin, Leo J. (Box 8)
  - A ternary phase solubility diagram of the system: Glycine-hydrobromic acid-water at 25' C, 1952; UA151.001.008.00385; Nickerson, Robert F. (Box 8)
  - A bomb-type calorimeter for the measurement of heats of hydrolysis of metals and metallic hydrides, 1953; UA151.001.008.00386; Thalmayer, Conrad E. (Box 8)
  - An investigation of the relationship between aqueous solutions of the decahydrates of sodium sulfate, sodium carbonate and sodium chromate, 1954; UA151.001.008.00387; Robbins, Martin Daniel (Box 8)
  - Attempted proof of structure of x(w-dicyanovinyl) pyrroline, 1955; UA151.001.008.00388; Anderson, George Joseph (Box 8)
  - The reduction of di-n-butyl peroxide by lithium aluminum hydride, 1955; UA151.001.008.00389; Cremer, Barbara (Box 8)
  - The stability of a biazonium salt in the presence of zinc chloride, 1955; UA151.001.008.00390; Luksin, Alexander A. (Box 8)
  - The excess ozonation of olefins, 1955; UA151.001.008.00391; Rapp, Robert D. (Box 8)
  - Attempted synthesis of pyrroline-2-aldehyde, 1956; UA151.001.008.00392; Fasciano, Robert Walter (Box 8)
  - A multi-orientation attachment for a petrographic microscope and its use in the identification of organic crystals, 1956; UA151.001.008.00393; Steinbach, Betty (Box 8)
  - The effect of thermal cycling on hydrogen uptake by metals, 1957; UA151.001.008.00394; Carlson, Elizabeth (Box 8)
  - Solid solutions in the system lithium fluoride-sodium fluoride, 1957; UA151.001.008.00395; Hobey, William D. (Box 8)
  - Infrared spectra of CH3CD3 and preparation of Mg2Ge, 1957; UA151.001.008.00396; Schneider, Carol J. (Box 8)
  - The heat of formation of magnesium hydride, 1958; UA151.001.008.00397; Avarbock, Harvey Sheldon (Box 8)
  - Determination of the density of metal hydrides by anaerobic helium displacement, 1958; UA151.001.008.00398; Lavenberg, Natalie J. (Box 8)
  - Phase diagram of the ternary system: alanine, hydrochloric acid and water, 1958; UA151.001.008.00399; Tesch, Audrey G. (Box 8)
  - Solid solutions in the system strontium bromide-calcium bromide, 1959; UA151.001.008.00400; Coleman, Irma (Box 8)
  - Solid solutions in the system lithium fluoride-nickelous fluoride, 1959; UA151.001.008.00401; Kinzler, David (Box 8)
  - A study of hydrogen absorption of metals and alloys, 1960; UA151.001.008.00402; Kostiner, Edward S. (Box 8)
  - Hydrogenation of 2, 5-di-t-butylhydroquinone, 1960; UA151.001.008.00403; Maier, Lawrence R. (Box 8)
  - The effect of sodium octyl sulfate on the chymotryptic hydrolysis of bovine serum albumin, 1960; UA151.001.008.00404; Possick, Paul Aaron (Box 8)
  - Ultraviolet light and the conversation of trypsinogen to trypain, 1960; UA151.001.008.00405; Schein, Nancy (Box 8)
  - Reduction of pyroglutamic acid to proline by lithium aluminum hydride, 1961; UA151.001.008.00406; Coco, Frank V. (Box 8)
  - The fractionation of a biologically active urinary gonadotropin, 1961; UA151.001.008.00407; Kaufman, Andrew B.; Solod, Eugene A. (Box 8)
  - Lattice spacings of the vanadium hydrogen system, 1961; UA151.001.008.00408; Knudsen, Judith E. (Box 8)
  - Systems of lithium fluoride with magnesium fluoride and magnesium oxide, 1961; UA151.001.008.00409; Lord, Harry (Box 8)
  - Effects of cation binding and nonaqueous solvents on protein spectra, 1962; UA151.001.008.00410; Appleton, Daniel (Box 8)
  - Separation of bound substances from serum albumins by gel filtration, 1962; UA151.001.008.00411; Baron, Paul David (Box 8)
  - The preparation and structure of barium lithium hydride, 1962; UA151.001.008.00412; Campbell, Judith A. (Box 8)
  - The binding of mercury II to cysteine and related compounds, 1962; UA151.001.008.00413; Colman, Gerald Byer (Box 8)
  - Syntheses of 4-hydroxycyclohexanones and 3-cyclohexenols, 1962; UA151.001.008.00414; Larsen, John W. (Box 8)
  - Syntheses of Phenol and cyclohexanol derivatives, 1963; UA151.001.008.00415; Henry, David J. (Box 8)
  - Preparation and reduction of 2, 5-dialkyl-4-hydroxybenzoic acids, 1964; UA151.001.008.00416; Cooper, Alan D. (Box 8)
  - Syntheses of 5-mehylcholestanone and 8B-methyl-delta 4,6-androstadience-3,17-dione, 1964; UA151.001.008.00417; Hickman, James J. (Box 8)
  - The microwave absorption of solutions of ammonia in carbon tetrachloride, 1964; UA151.001.008.00418; Nunes, Thomas L. (Box 8)
  - Atomic structure of the first row elements: Calculations of electronic charge density, 1964; UA151.001.008.00419; Raffenetti, Richard C. (Box 8)
  - Synthesis of cis and trans dialdehyde anthracene adducts, 1964; UA151.001.009.00420; Sahatjian, Ronald A. (Box Shared 25)
  - Syntheses leading to a study of the dienone to phenol rearrangement of n-methyl-8-aza-spiro-(4,5)-deca-1, 4-dienne-3-one, 1965; UA151.001.009.00421; Horsting, Maryka (Box Shared 25)
  - Synthesis of 8B-methyl-delta5-cholestene-3-B-ol, 1965; UA151.001.009.00422; MacLachlan, James D. (Box Shared 25)
  - Solute-solute, solute-solvent effects and true integrated absorption intensities of the s-h stretching vibration in the liquid state, 1966; UA151.001.009.00423; Levine, David M. (Box Shared 25)
  - NMR and equilibration studies of the 2, 5-dimethyl-1, 4-cyclohexanediolds, 1966; UA151.001.009.00424; Boschetto, David J. (Box Shared 25)
  - Line broadening in the x-ray diffraction patterns of the vanadium hydrogen system, 1966; UA151.001.009.00425; MacMillan, John H. (Box Shared 25)
  - Dipole moment function by the determination of the molecular Zeeman Effect, 1966; UA151.001.009.00426; Wolken, George T. S. Jr. (Box Shared 25)
  - The conformational equilibrium of neoisomenthol, 1967; UA151.001.009.00427; Abbott, Richard E. (Box Shared 25)
  - The attempted synthesis and coordination of 1, 4, 7-triazocyclononane, 1967; UA151.001.009.00428; Bennett, Charles R. (Box Shared 25)
  - Effects of water vapor on the viability of freeze-dried serratia marcescens and escherichia coli, 1967; UA151.001.009.00429; Schaefer, Lawrence M. (Box Shared 25)
- Graduate Theses, 1909 -- 1925; UA151.002; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains the Department of Chemistry graduate theses.
  - The utilization of a waste product, 1909; UA151.002.001.00001; Clough, Ray William (Box Shared 25)
  - Cyanide experiments with a Mexican silver ore, 1911; UA151.002.001.00002; Baker, Crosby F. (Box Shared 25)
  - The influence of constitution on the reactivity of carbonyl derivatives, 1911; UA151.002.001.00003; Fuller, George Prescott (Box Shared 25)
  - The hydrolysis of phosphorus pentoxide, 1914; UA151.002.001.00004; Phelps, Edward P. (Box Shared 25)
  - The influence of constitution on the reactivity of carbonyl derivatives, 1915; UA151.002.001.00005; Savage, Harold R. (Box Shared 25)
  - A density table for solutions of formaldehyde in water prepared from commercial formaldehyde manufactured in the United States, 1915; UA151.002.001.00006; Aspinwall, Frederick Otto (Box Shared 25)
  - The peroxide fusion method for the determination of sulphur in coal, 1915; UA151.002.001.00007; O'Meara, Francis (Box Shared 25)
  - A study of several methods for extracting caffeine from coffee without injuring its flavor, 1916; UA151.002.001.00008; Phillips, Ralph Oliver (Box Shared 25)
  - The velocity with which certain cobalt ammines rearrange themselves in aqueous solution, 1917; UA151.002.001.00009; Holden, Kathryn (Box Shared 25)
  - Sources of tannins for mordanting cotton in the application of the azo dyes, 1917; UA151.002.001.00010; Staples, Carl W. (Box Shared 25)
  - The manufacture of picric acid by the sodium nitrate method, 1918; UA151.002.001.00011; Lybeck, Robert Ferdinand (Box Shared 25)
  - The addition of sodium malonic ester to aromatic mustard oils, 1920; UA151.002.001.00012; Clough, Woodman W. (Box Shared 25)
  - Production of metallic cesium from pollucite and its action on some organic compounds, 1922; UA151.002.001.00013; Cushing, Lovell M. (Box Shared 25)
  - Tung oil and sesame oil as a possible soap stock, 1922; UA151.002.001.00014; Falk, Arthur Herman (Box Shared 25)
  - Action of potassium hydroxide on the monothioanilides of certain alkylated ethylacetomalonates, 1922; UA151.002.001.00015; Pratt, Malcolm Field (Box Shared 25)
  - On the alkylation of 2-amino p-cymene, 1925; UA151.002.001.00016; Gold, Louis Hyman (Box Shared 25)
  - The preparation and reactions of para dimethyl amino phenyl isothiocyanate, 1925; UA151.002.001.00017; Leavitt, Paul L. (Box Shared 25)
- Photographs and slides, 1990 -- 2010; UA151.003
  This series is open for research.
  This series contains digital photographs and historical slides created by the Department of Chemistry.
  - Chemistry photographs, 1990 -- 2010; UA151-002
  - Historical slides (college) prepared by Professor Crosby F. Baker, UA151-003 (Box 1)
    Box of lantern slides; also contains 5 pages of historical comments by Professor Crosby F. Baker (for bio see vertical file) regarding the individual slides. Slides and comments have to be compared as numbers are off slightly. Contains the oldest photograph of Ballou Hall and the Hill (around 1852 or 1853) currently known as well as historical facts relating to various buildings, various chemistry labs, the quarry, Nick Dwyer, architect drawings, labs, assaying, Murdena Cambell, the old 'balance' donated to Tufts in 1857 and a 1939 chowder party. Most of the slides say Munro on them.
    Department of Chemistry; Banks (buildings); Baker, Crosby F.
- Publications, circa 1990 -- 2010; UA151.000451
  This series contains graduate and fellowship brochures created by the Department of Chemistry.
  - Graduate and fellowship brochures, UA151-001 (Box 1)
- Elena Rybak-Akimova records, circa 1997 -- 2018; UA151.000452; Rybak-Akimova, Elena, 1962-2018; 14 Linear Feet 14 record cartons
  Records containing information related to student education, staff and faculty employment, and Board of Trustees records are closed for 75 years from the date of creation. This series may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
  This series is arranged in received order.
  This series contains materials created or compiled by Elena Rybak-Akimova, Tufts professor of chemistry from 1997 until her death in 2018. The series contains chemistry course materials such as syllabi, transparencies, readings, and exams. It also includes committee records, project files, conference records, and grad student records, documenting Rybak-Akimova's professional activities at Tufts and in the field of chemistry.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred by the Chemistry Department, May 21, 2021, accession UA-2021-051.
  - Project files, circa 1990s -- 2000s; UA151.000453; 2 Folder(s) (Box 1)
    75 years from date of creation.
  - Project files; Chem 1 course materials and department files, circa 1990s -- 2010s; UA151.000454 (Box 2)
  - Chem 1 course materials and department files; Chem 161 course materials, circa 1990s -- 2010s; UA151.000455 (Box 3)
  - Chem 161 course materials, circa 2000s -- 2010s; UA151.000456 (Box 4)
  - Chem 161, Chem 2, and Chem 164 course materials, circa 1990s -- 2010s; UA151.000457 (Box 5)
  - Chem 2 and Chem 164 course materials, circa 1990s -- 2010s; UA151.000458 (Box 6)
  - Chem 161, Chem 162, Chem 164, Chem 165, Chem 268 course materials, circa 2010s; UA151.000459 (Box 7)
  - Chem 161, Chem 162, Chem 164, Chem 165, Chem 268 course materials, circa 2010s; UA151.000460 (Box 8)
  - Mixed files including course materials and abstracts, circa 2000s; UA151.000461 (Box 9)
  - Chem 162 and Chem 268 course materials, circa 2000s -- 2010s; UA151.000462 (Box 10)
  - Chem 162 and Chem 268 course materials, circa 2000s -- 2010s; UA151.000463 (Box 11)
  - Book draft, dept. files, grad program records, instrument committee records, circa 1997 -- 2015; UA151.000464 (Box 12)
  - Chem 161, Chem 162, Chem 164 course materials; student work, circa 2006 -- 2017; UA151.000465 (Box 13)
  - Hard drives, CDs, thumb drives, circa 1990s -- 2010s; UA151.000466 (Box 14)